Takuji Okubo

takuji.okubo@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/takuji-o-85ba94191

Github: https://github.com/tak-9/ Website: https://tak-9.github.io/

Summary

An IT engineer in Sydney with a total of 19 years of experience in various roles as a Java developer tester, support engineer, Unix administrator and technical translator.

Tested and developed new features of an open source Java EE application server, Glassfish, for one of the largest IT service companies for 7 years. Fixed bugs and suggested solutions to the open source developers. Represented a team of three developers from Sydney and liaised with a large overseas development team using the Japanese language skill. Communicated effectively with Australian team members and Japanese customers using bilingual skill to deliver product on time with tight schedule.

Passionate about learning new technologies. In order to update skills with the latest full stack Web development technologies, currently undertaking 24 weeks of intensive course, Coding Boot Camp, at the University of Sydney due to be completed in May 2020. Learnt full-stack web technologies including JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, Bootstrap, HTML, Node.js and git in short time by this intensive course.

Technical Skills

Java EE, J2EE, Glassfish, Junit, Selenium, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Oracle, Postgres, Eclipse, Git, Subversion, maven, ant, bash, Windows, Linux, Solaris, Testing, Debugging, Troubleshooting

Communication Skills

- Customer facing experience both working with customers face to face and remotely over the phone and email.
- Represented a team of three developers from Sydney and liaised with overseas clients using the Japanese language skill.
- Worked at customer sites for analysing requirements, implementing and supporting both development and production systems.
- Communicated with users in Asia and Pacific region by email and phone to resolve technical issues.
- Wrote storage management software product manuals. Analysed issues with existing software manuals and re-structured it to improve the product.

Employment

Fujitsu Australia Software Technology, Sydney, 2007 – 2019

 Fujitsu Australia Software Technology (FAST) is a research and development organisation for software products. My main roles in the company includes being:

(a) Java EE Application Server Engineer (7 years)

- Fujitsu uses "Glassfish" (open source product) as a base for their commercial version of Java EE application server product "Interstage Application Server".
- Worked in collaboration with the Fujitsu Japan's product development team for testing the product as well as developing new features.
- As a bilingual engineer, represented the Australian team of three developers and liaised with Fujitsu Japan.
- Tested JDBC and JPA with the following RDBMS:
 Oracle, Postgres, SQL Server, JavaDB and Fujitsu Symfoware
- Fixed Glassfish bugs with Eclipse debugger and reported bugs to Glassfish developers with suggested fixes.
- Made modifications to the Glassfish Web Admin Console.
- Written test cases and developed automatic testing program for Web Admin.
- Researched on Glassfish modular architecture (OSGi) for adding new functionalities such as creating a new log file.
- Developed installation and configuration tools with ansible, bash, batch file, VBScripts and Java XML API.

(b) C# and Postgres Developer and Tester (6 months)

- Fujitsu PalmSecure is a security software product using biometric technology.
- Developed a new feature to support PostgreSQL in addition to SQLServer.
- Ported stored procedures from SQL Server to PostgreSQL and updated C# application to support another database driver. The product was originally developed in C# and SQL Server.
- Developed an automatic test program for Fujitsu PalmSecure software in C#.

(c) Web Application Tester (1 year)

- Tested Web admin for Fujitsu's business process management software product.
- Created automated testing scripts with Selenium WebDriver in Java.

(d) Storage Management Software (1 year)

 Tested Admin Console for a backup software which is designed for Fujitsu's disk arrays in SAN environment. Made suggestions for improvement of user experience (UX) and user interface (UI) of the product. Analysed issues with the existing manuals, re-structured and rewrote them to improve the product.

(e) Technical Translator (2 year)

- Translated software UI and manuals to/from Japanese and English.
- Assisted other translators without IT background with technical questions.
- Provided demo and training on a translation tool for other translators.

Symantec, Sydney, Technical Support Engineer, 2006 –2007

• Technical support for "Symantec i3" which provides application performance management solution for J2EE servers such as Websphere or WebLogic.

Computer Associates, Sydney, Associate Technical Support Engineer 2005 –2006

• Acted as a front line of support for various CA products and provided translation for English speaking support engineers in Australia and customers in Japan.

Fujitsu Chubu Systems Limited, Japan, Systems Engineer, 1998 –2003

- Worked as a systems administrator and developer for Toyota Motor Corporation.
- Worked on site and built good relationship with the clients and successfully completed several large and small projects with short deadlines.

(a) Solaris Systems Administrator (4 years)

- Analysed customer's requirements and designed recommended hardware and software configurations.
- Setup production and development environments consisted of the following products: Solaris, Interstage, iPlanet Web Server, Oracle 8i database servers, storage area network and disk arrays.
- Setup and managed Oracle. Created database backup and restore scripts.
- Performed troubleshooting, identified the root cause of the issue to implement a permanent fix to prevent the same issue from occurring again.
- Provided training for other team members on systems administration.

(b) Software Developer (1 year)

 Developed Web applications and database scripts with the following technologies:

Java, ASP, CGI, HTML, Photoshop, Infomix, C, Oracle Pro*C and PL/SQL.

Education

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Sydney, 2019-To be completed in 2020

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express & ReactJS

University of Sydney, 2003 –2005

Master of Applied Information Technology, Software Engineering Major

Macquarie University, Sydney 1996

Studied for a year as an Exchange Student from Nagoya Gakuin University

Nagoya Gakuin University, Japan 1994 –1998

Bachelor of Arts, Faculty of Foreign Studies, English Department

Certifications

Sun Certified Programmer for the Java 2 Platform Standard Edition, 2005

Oracle Master 8i Gold, 2003

- · Certified by Oracle Japan
- Exam subjects includes SQL, PL/SQL and Database Administration

Class II Information Technology Engineer, 1998

- Certified by the Japanese Ministry of International Trade and Industry
- Knowledge on software development process, project management, network, database and C programming are required to pass the exam.